So after we develop a model,
那么在建立模型之后 我们想知道它的性能如何
we want to find out how good it is.
这是一个有难度的问题 但在这部分
This is a difficult question.
But in this section, we'll learn
我们将学习一些不同的指标 通过它们来了解模型的好坏
a few different metrics that will tell us how good our model is.
我们来看两个主要示例
So we're going to look at two main examples.
第一个示例中的模型用于检测特定疾病
The first example is a model that will help us detect a particular illness,
判断就诊者是健康还是患病
and tell if a patient is healthy or sick.
第二个示例是一个垃圾邮件检测器 将帮助我们确定
The second example will be a spam detector,
which will help us determine if an email is spam or not.
电子邮件是否为垃圾邮件
例如 左边
For example, on the left,
是来自奶奶的电子邮件 你不想将它标记为垃圾邮件
you have an email from your grandma,
which you don't want to label a spam.
右边很明显是一封垃圾邮件
On the right, you have an email that is
clearly spam and you want to send that to the spam folder.
你要将其送到垃圾邮件文件夹
我们来看看用于诊断疾病的模型
So let's look at the model for diagnosing an illness.
总共有四种情况
There are four possible cases.
当就诊者患病 且模型阳性确诊断为患病时
When a patient is sick,
and the model correctly diagnosed them as sick.
这是一名患者 我需要让他入院进行进一步检查或治疗
This is a sick patient,
I will send in for further examination or for treatment.
这种情况我们称之为真阳性
This case, we'll call a true positive.
当就诊者未患病 而且模型阳性确诊断为健康时
When a patient is healthy and the model correctly diagnosed him as healthy,
这是一名健康就诊者 可以直接回家
this is a healthy patient that we'll send home.
此情况我们称之为真阴性
This case, we call a true negative.
当就诊者患病而模型错误诊断为健康时
When a patient is sick and the modeling correctly diagnosed them as healthy.
这是个错误
This is a mistake,
说明我们在让患者未接受治疗的情况下回家了
and it means we'll be sending a sick patient back home with no treatment.
这称为假阴性
This is called a false negative.
最终当就诊者健康
And finally, when a patient is healthy and the model incorrectly diagnoses them as sick.
而模型错误诊断为患病时 这也是错误的
This is also a mistake,
说明我们让一名未患病者入院进行进一步检查或治疗
and it means we'll be sending a healthy person for further examination or treatment.
这称为假阳性
This is called a false positive.
现在我们介绍一个所谓的混淆矩阵
Now, we'll introduce what's called the confusion matrix.
这是一个用于描述模型性能的表
This is a table that will describe the performance of a model.
在这个模型中 我们有 10,000 个患者
In this model, we have 10,000 patients.
其中有 1,000 是患病的 并且被阳性确诊断为患病
A thousand of them are sick and have been correctly diagnosed as sick.
我们称之为真阳性
We call these true positive.
有 200 人是患病的 而被错误诊断为健康
200 of them are sick and have been incorrectly diagnosed them as healthy.
我们称之为假阴性
So we call them false negatives.
有 800 名就诊者是健康的 而被错误诊断为患病
800 patients are healthy and have been incorrectly diagnosed as sick.
我们称之为假阳性
We call these false positives.
最后 有 8,000 名就诊者是健康的
And finally, 8,000 patients are healthy and have been correctly diagnosed as healthy.
并被阳性确诊断为健康 我们称之为真阴性
We call these true negatives.
混淆矩阵只是存储这四个值的表格
The confusion matrix is a simple table that stores these four values.
现在我们来看一下用于检测垃圾邮件的模型
Now let's look at the model for detecting spam email.
共有四种可能的情况
There are four possible cases.
当我们收到垃圾邮件 并且分类器阳性确地将其发送到我们的垃圾邮件
When we get a spam email and the classifier sends it to
a spam folder correctly, which is a true positive.
文件夹时 这为真阳性
当我们收到垃圾邮件
When we get a spam email and the classifier incorrectly sends it to our inbox,
而分类器错误地将其发送到我们的收件箱时 这为假阴性
this is a false negative.
当我们收到奶奶的阳性常邮件 而分类器
When we get a good email, for example,
from our grandma and the classifier incorrectly sends it to our spam folder,
错误地将它发送到我们的垃圾邮件文件夹时 此为假阳性
this is called a false positive.
最后 当我们收到阳性常邮件
And finally, when we get a good email the classifier correctly sends it to our inbox,
分类器阳性确地将其发送到我们的收件箱时 此为真阴性
which is a true negative.
我们也可以找到这个模型的混淆矩阵
And we can also find the confusion matrix for this model.
这里共有 1000 封电子邮件
Here, we have a pool of a thousand emails.
其中
Out of these emails, 100 spam emails have been correctly sent to the spam folder.
100 封垃圾邮件被阳性确发送到垃圾邮件文件夹
170 封垃圾邮件被错误发送到收件箱中
170 spam emails have been incorrectly sent to the inbox.
30 封非垃圾邮件被错误发送到垃圾邮件文件夹
30 non-spam emails have been incorrectly sent to the spam folder.
最后 700 封非垃圾邮件被阳性确发送到收件箱中
And finally, 700 non-spam emails have been correctly sent to the inbox.
这是它的混淆矩阵
So here is the confusion matrix.
现在轮到你创建一个混淆矩阵了
Now it's your turn to create a confusion matrix.
看看这些数据 其中蓝点为阳性
Look at this data where the blue points are positive,
红点为阴性
and the red points are negative.
我们训练的模型是一条将它们分开的直线 阳性点区域
The model we've trained is the line that separates them,
with the positive region being in the top,
在上 阴性点区域在下
and the negative region in the bottom.
现在 填写以下混淆矩阵中的四个空白处
Now please fill in the following four blanks in
the confusion matrix for number of true positives,
分别写上真阳性、真阴性、假阳性
true negatives, false positives, and false negatives.
和假阴性